### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/tramnguyen-1999a434 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

English Teaching
Warehouse Operations
International Logistics

## Languages

English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

Google UX Design Professional Agile Project Management Introduction to Scrum Master Training Introduction to Data Analytics

Honors-Awards
Best Teaching Assistant

# Tram Nguyen

Technical Business Analyst Vietnam

# Summary

Graduated from Antwerp Management School as a Master of Global Supply Chain Management with Distinct result. Having 9 years working in Supply Chain with knowledge in Import/Export procedure, International trade practice, Procurement, Supplier Management, Transportation and 3PL Logistics Management. Since 2017, experienced career shifting into Software Application Functional Consulting - involving Project Management, studying WMS - Warehouse Management System/ OMS - Order Management System concept, actively proposing the design in HMS - Haulage Management System which has proven to be applicable and considered as an operation productivity enhancements for several Singapore Transport/ Container Services companies.

# Experience

NAB Innovation Centre Vietnam
Technical Business Analyst
June 2022 - Present (2 years 10 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Four Hands
Business System Analyst
December 2020 - May 2022 (1 year 6 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Collaborate with the ERP Project Management and Technology teams to plan, execute and maintain continued implementation of ORACLE NetSuite Build and maintain training material and SOPs

Assist on-site continuous end-user training and UAT

Aid in the planning and execution of change management activities

INFOLOG Logistics & Supply Chain Software
Project Manager cum Application Functional Consultant
September 2018 - September 2020 (2 years 1 month)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Analyze customer's business requirements relating to warehousing and transportation managements.

Liaise with IT teams for technical solutions

Monitor project timeline and progress

Prepare documents including technical and business solutions

Perform system testing and master data setup

Support customers remotely via chatgroups, phone calls or onsite for User

Testing, System Acceptance Test and System Go Live

Support - Provide training and coaching for new staff

New Viet Dairy WMS Project Manager October 2017 - August 2018 (11 months)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Collect Master Data, coordinate relating departments in implementing the new Warehouse Management System.

Monitor the project budget, timeline and prepare Work Instructions for warehouse staffs.

Organize necessary training, UAT, collect feedback from key users for essential modifications and customization of the software to best fit the business context.

Closely coordinate with software vendor for system error fixing, new change requests and business solutions and do testing.

### Ter Beke

Consulting Project April 2017 - June 2017 (3 months)

Belgium

Consulting Project to obtain the Master Degree in Antwerp Management School

The Project is mainly about Sales and Operations Planning ( S&OP) to solve obsoletes and enhance service level for food processing company.

Main recommendations: CPFR Model, Customization Postponements, Scenario Planning, Standard Operating Procedures and Customer Prioritization.

Antwerp Management School
Full-time Master Student of Global Supply Chain Management
September 2016 - June 2017 (10 months)

Antwerp Area, Belgium

#### Main Coursework:

Basics of Supply Chain Management, Distribution Structures and Outbound Logistics, Modelling Global Supply Chain, Production and Operational Excellence, Strategic Procurement, Supply Chain Implementation Aspects.

New Viet Dairy Import Executive July 2013 - August 2016 (3 years 2 months) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Vietnam leading importer of dairyproducts along with other high end food products distributing by professionally developed Foodservice and Retails Channels.

Critical partnerships: Fonterra (World's largest exporter of dairy), Conaprole (Largest dairy company in Uruguay), Lamb Weston (The largest potato company in North America), Heinz, Friesland Campina...

### Activities and Responsibility:

- Monitor purchase orders, schedule the transport of shipments, track shipping schedules and check import documents
- Solve problems arising during shipments.
- Compare costs and select reliable transport service providers.

#### **ILA Vietnam**

Teaching Assistant and Level Tester August 2011 - August 2015 (4 years 1 month) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Support English teachers in class activities and young learners who are in need of additional help.
- Distribute and grade tests and homework assignments.
- Observe students' performance and monthly inform the parents about students' progress or problems.
- Be a level tester to determine the appropriate level English of children and teenagers throughout speaking test. Vinhlong

Vinh Long Cereal and Food Corporation
Import Export Coordinator
February 2011 - November 2012 (1 year 10 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Activities and Responsibility:

- Handle customers' request for import / export shipments, coordinate with warehouse staff, carriers, shipping agencies, inspectors and customers to ensure smooth import/ export transactions.
- Prepare shipping documents, check and open Letter of Credit.
- Ensure prompt delivery of cargo, keep track of shipment payments and handle claims with insurance companies if any shipment problems happen to occur.

### Education

Antwerp Management School

Master of Arts - MA, Logistics, Materials, and Supply Chain

Management · (2016 - 2017)

The American TESOL Institute
TESOL Certificate, Teaching English to speakers of other languages · (2016)

University of Economics in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), International Business (2007 - 2011)